Buhari Maiwada

website: https://bsoftmaewada.github.io/my-portfolio/

About Me

A bachelor degree graduate in computer engineering and a certified software engineer. Experienced working with programming languages such as Java, JavaScript, C, Python, Assembly language, and VHDL. Software developing and deploying, testing, debugging code, and using compute engines on Azure, Google cloud. Other technologies used are Jenkins, docker, JUnit, Spring Boot, and Angular framework Also, have experience working with microcontrollers (STM32, Arduino, Raspberry Pi), designing interfaces, operating systems, embedded systems, and administering systems networks and IoT (Internet of Things).

Quick to learn and master new technologies, successful working in both team and self-directed settings.

Experience

INFOSYS ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July 2022 - Till Date

- Junior assistant to client project production team.
- Fullstack, Frontend and Backend web developer.
- Assist senior software developers with the deploying and development client applications.
- Writing software code in java programming language
- Troubleshooting issues with software applications, and performing unit testing of software applications.
- Designing APIs using mule 4 and Anypoint platform/studio.

REVATURE FULL-STACK JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Feb 2022 – July 2022

Technical Skills Summary:

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS
- Microservices: Spring Boot, GCP instances, HttpClient, Docker, REST
- DevOps: Jerkins, Postman, Docker, Gradle, GitHub, GitHub Action
- Server Technologies: Postgres SQL, JDBC, Hibernate, Tomcat, Spring MVC
- Web Technologies: Angular, Gradle, Spring, Spring Boot, Javalin

GENERAL ASSEMBLY (REMOTE) FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug 2020 – Nov 2021

- Fullstack, Frontend and Backend web developer.
- Coding using languages such as: JavaScript, Python and C.
- Knowledge on fundamentals of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Experience using frameworks such as NodeJS, Express JS, React JS and Django.
- Knowledge on JavaScript ES6 features such as classes, arrow functions, string templates, REST/spread operators, promises, async/await.
- Debugging, deploy, testing codes and seeking answers to problems.
- Using git and GitHub during the training with instructors and collaborate with coworkers on team projects.
- Working with other technologies like GitHub, VSCode, Insomia, Discord, Slack.
- Working with Database PostgreSQL, MongoDB and Heroku.
- Keeping track of changes made to code with Git version control system.

Skills

Software Engineering:

Languages:

- Java
- Python
- C Programming
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- RAML
- SQL

Web Technologies:

- Angular
- REACT JS
- HTML 5
- CSS 5
- Embedded JavaScript
- Django
- ExpressJS
- Node.JS

Microservices:

- GCP Cloud
- Spring Boot
- Docker
- Eureka

DevOps

- Git
- GitHub
- Jerkins
- Docker
- SonaCloud

Server Technologies:

- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- Javalin
- Spring Data
- Spring MVC
- Tomcat
- Hibernate

Data Structure:

- Data Structure
- Algorithm
- Big O notation
- Binar Search
- Sorting









Projects

REVATURE

SpaceEco

SpaceEco is an intergalactic, after-market e-commerce site that allows users to buy and sell items associated with interstellar life

Roles / Responsibilities

- Collaborated with other team members in designing and developing both the frontend and backend.
- Achieved Object Oriented Programming principles to structure the project.
- Deployed GCP instances to host web pages and servers.
- Managed project dependencies on the backend with Gradle.
- Implemented Spring MVC to host TomCat and create the server.
- Implemented Spring ORM to map model objects and create a relationship between them.
- Implemented Spring AOP to log any errors.
- Used Mockito and JUnit for unit testing.
- Used Spring MVC for request/response handling.
- Utilized Jasmine and Karma for client side testing.

Environment / Technologies

Angular 2+, Gradle, Git, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Spring Data, Spring Test, DevOps, Jenkins, TDD, SQL, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, JavaScript, GCP Compute Engine, GCP Cloud SQL, Sonarcloud, REST, Spring Boot, JUnit, Mockito, MockMVC, Docker

Track2gether

Track2gether, a budget tracker, is an application that helps to keep an accurate record of your money inflow and outflow. It allows you to monitor and categorize your income sources and expenses. Without the help of a fancy financial planner, we provide an easy and light way to monitor and track your income and expenses for you to have a better idea of you and your partner's financial status by providing visualized data on financial history.

Roles / Responsibilities

- Worked with Intellij IDEA 2022 and Visual Studio Code.
- Used Spring Boot java framework to developed the backend.
- Used Hibernate to abstract the JDBC. Deployed GCP instances to host web pages and
- Created an image of the app using Docker containers.
- Created a single page application using Angular
- Used Mockito and JUnit/Spring Boot Test for server side testing
- Set up Embedded H2 database for testing
- Utilized Jasmine and Karma for client side testing
- Implemented WebClient for cross service communication
- Used JWTs for user session management

Environment / Technologies

Angular 2+, Gradle, Git, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Spring Data, Spring Test, DevOps, Jenkins, TDD, SQL, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, JavaScript, GCP Compute Engine, GCP Cloud SQL, Sonarcloud, REST, Spring Boot, JUnit, Mockito, MockMVC

Expense Reimbursement System (ERS)

The Expense Reimbursement System (ERS) will manage the process of reimbursing employees for expenses incurred while on company time. All employees in the company can login and submit requests for reimbursement and view their past tickets and pending requests. Finance managers can log in and view all reimbursement requests and past history for all employees in the company. Finance managers are authorized to approve and deny requests for expense reimbursement.

Roles / Responsibilities

- Created a full-stack application with JavaScript in the frontend and Java in the
- Utilized JDBC to talk to PostgreSQL to store data.
- Formed interactive web pages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript Used HTTP sessions for session management Implemented Object Oriented Programming (OOP) to structure Project. Used Gradle to manage the application's dependencies Applied BootStrap's API to style most of the webpages. Requested data in form of JSON from backend and Fetch. Hosted codebase in the GitLab. Overviewed version control with Git.

Computer Engineering:

- Assembly Language
- VHDL/Verilog
- **FreeRTOS**
- Embedded-C firmware and drivers
- Peripherals (USB. PWM. SPI. ADC, UART and DMA)
- Microcontrollers (STM32, Arduino)
- Raspberry Pi
- IoT (Internet of Things)
- **Smart Sensors**
- Designing interfaces
- Hardware Design
- Computer Networking and Wireless
- Embedded system
- Operating systems (RTOS, GPOS)

Education

Bachelor of Science:

Computer Engineering (IoT)

Gradualed Dec. 2020.

Minnesota State University Mankato, MN









github.com/in/bsoftmaewada

Projects

Expense Reimbursement System (ERS)

The Expense Reimbursement System (ERS) will manage the process of reimbursing employees for expenses incurred while on company time. All employees in the company can login and submit requests for reimbursement and view their past tickets and pending requests. Finance managers can log in and view all reimbursement requests and past history for all employees in the company. Finance managers are authorized to approve and deny requests for expense reimbursement.

Roles / Responsibilities

- Created a full-stack application with JavaScript in the frontend and Java in the backend.
- Utilized JDBC to talk to PostgreSQL to store data.
- Formed interactive web pages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Used HTTP sessions for session management
- Implemented Object Oriented Programming (OOP) to structure Project.
- Used Gradle to manage the application's dependencies
- Applied BootStrap's API to style most of the webpages.
- Requested data in form of JSON from backend and Fetch.
- Hosted codebase in the GitLab.
- Overviewed version control with Git.

Environment / Technologies

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, AJAX, SQL, Java, Javalin, Mockito, JUnit, JDBC

Internships

AT&T Sommer Learning Academy May – Aug 2020

Volunteer Experience

American Red Cross, Minnesota







